

Professional Summary

- 6+ years of experience in designing, developing, and delivering highly scalable enterprise wide applications and platform components deployed on-premises and on the cloud using open source as well as proprietary tools and services in the healthcare domain.
- Key strengths include sharp analytical skills, constant focus on quality and process improvements, good software engineering and problem-solving capabilities along with excellent communication skills to engage business and technology stakeholders.

Technical Skills

Amey Rupji

Programming Languages

Databases

Frameworks

DevOps

Platforms

Web Servers

• Cloud Platforms

Others

: C#, .Net, C++, C, CSS, JavaScript, HTML, Python, PySpark, Scala

: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL

: .Net, Django, jQuery, Node.js, Bootstrap

: Git, Jenkins, CircleCI, New Relic, Splunk, Atlassian Suite of Products

: Apple (macOS), Windows, Linux (Basics)

: Internet Information Services (IIS), Apache Tomcat, Nginx (Reverse Proxy)

: AWS (EC2, Lambda, S3, SNS, SQS, CloudWatch, AutoScaling, EMR, DynamoDB), Terraform

: Service Orient Architecture (SOA), Test Driven Development (TDD), MVC, REST

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, UnitedHealth Group

Apr 2015 - Present

- Developed a scalable cloud-based data mastering platform to consolidate, organize, aggregate, and enrich healthcare entities like Patients, Providers, Payors, and Practices.
- Implemented model and rule based distributed matching algorithm to link healthcare entities form disparate data sources each having millions of records for batch and streaming use cases.
- Worked with 6+ teams across the globe to support use cases like Health System Planning, Patient Care Coordination, Consumer Outreach Initiatives to drive healthy outcomes for patients.
- Collaborated with teams to implement the best practices in Cloud Infrastructure Automation, Cloud Application Security, Data Governance, and Data Stewardship. Onboarded and mentored new developers and members of partnering products on various aspects of the product through hands on training and technical product documentation.
- Technologies and tools used: Apple, Atlassian Products, AWS, Django, Git, GitHub, IntelliJ, Jenkins, Linux, New Relic, Postgres, Python, PyCharm, PySpark, Scala, Splunk, and Terraform.

Software Engineer, The Advisory Board Company (UnitedHealth Group)

Dec 2013 – Mar 2015

- Developed and maintained user facing website and backend web services to deploy websites and web api applications for single and multi-tenant SaaS products within the company.
- This empowered 4+ product teams easily scale their SaaS offerings to hundreds of health system clients maintaining their Service Level Agreements.
- Enhanced the Single Sign On platform by adding new functionalities and making it more robust by improving on existing testing infrastructure. Demonstrated ownership by handling numerous product integrations on the developed Single Sign-On platform by collaborating with Team Leads, Developers, Quality Assurance, and Services Team from these products.
- Technologies and tools used: Atlassian Products, C#, CSS, .Net MVC, NHibernate, SQL Server, Git, HTML, JavaScript, New Relic, REST Api Design, Rhino Moq, Splunk, StructureMap, and Windows.

Associate Software Engineer, The Advisory Board Company (UnitedHealth Group)

Sep 2012 – Nov 2013

- Collaborated with Product Management, User Experience, Engineering Teams, Quality Assurance, Services and Stakeholders to evangelize, organize, and develop a Single Sign-On platform for the company using SAML 2.0 protocol.
- Worked with 10+ internal product teams to replace their ad-hoc password protection policies for their users my migrating them over to the SSO platform using stateless RESTful web services combined with intuitive workflow application. This enabled end users of the system to have a more secure and unified experience to numerous SaaS offerings within the company. This implementation also supported Federated Single Sign-On Experience for users of configured clients.
- Robustness and reliability of the application was ensured by building in house testing frameworks. These frameworks eased extensibility of Unit, Integration, Functional and Regression Tests and supported Test Driven Development.
- Technologies and tools used: Atlassian Products, C#, CSS, .Net MVC, NHibernate, SQL Server, Git, HTML, JavaScript, New Relic, REST Api Design, Rhino Moq, Splunk, Ninject, and Windows.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Mumbai University, Mumbai, India

Graduated: Aug 2012

Graduated: May 2010

